Hi everybody, I'm Ina Garten and you're here in my barn in East Hampton, New York.
Have a very good time and don't forget the cocktails.
Delicious! So today I'm going to show you around my kitchen. Well, it's my office really and I'm
going to show you a few of my favorite things. This barn is actually a great luxury for me because I
used to work and film in my house. That was crazy and so now I get to walk across the lawn
and go to work and then when I'm done I can close the door and leave work behind me.
One of the things I do in my kitchen to make everything really simple is I don't have a
lot of fancy equipment. I have just things that anybody else would have in their kitchen.
Maybe a few more but not a lot. Nothing that anybody can have themselves. I'm going to start
with three things on the counter that I like to have out all the time. First because they're better
at room temperature like garlic and oranges, eggs are better at room temperature on baking,
and lemons are better at room temperature because they have more juice. I'm always picking up something
and stirring or tasting something and I just buy antique silver spoons. They're really inexpensive
and I just put them in a jar and leave them on the counter. A few spatulas. And the third thing is
butcher blocks. They're really important. I have lots of them and if you take care of them they last
forever. Two years ago when I thought about writing a cookbook that was going to come out in October
of 2020, I thought well there's going to be an election in November and everybody's going to be
stressed so I'm going to write a cookbook about comfort food and I thought well modern comfort
food would be great because it's fresher, it's easier to make, it's kind of more delicious.
Little did I know. Turns out we all needed this right now. So Thanksgiving is actually usually
in the barn at this big long table but this year's going to be really different. It's going to be
Jeffrey and me in quarantine. I'll probably make a very small turkey and I think we're going to have
a very good time. Okay now I'm going to take you to the stove and I'm going to show you four things
that I absolutely adore. The first thing's salt. I have three salts that I use all the time. First
one's kosher salt and I use diamond crystal kosher salt. It's actually different from other
kosher salt. Some of them are much saltier and so you have to be careful if you use a different
kind. The second one is French sea salt. It's called fleur de sel. I use it to finish things.
It's kind of just lightly briny and the third one I use from time to time is mold and flake sea salt
and what I like is when I'm doing like a pastry crust like a chicken pot pie or something I'll
brush it with egg wash and just sprinkle it with salt and pepper and that flake salt just looks
gorgeous and that crunchiness tastes great. So three salts I always use and then these are really
important. Timers. I have lots of timers. I don't want to put something in the oven and forget about
it which I can do and the next thing is I have lots of oven thermometers because no matter what
it says on the dial the oven itself could be totally different. Okay now I'm going to give you a
little tour of the pantry. I have food on one side and I have equipment on the other side. I'll show
you. Oh I forgot I have to stop. So this is all the equipment and look who's a Dutch ovens and
dishes that I use a lot and big pans, knife sharpeners, everything you need and then this is the
pantry side. This is all the food. It's not the neatest pantry in the world but it's not the worst.
Okay I'm back. Let me show you some things over here that I love. One is my kitchen scale. I use
it all the time. So if something says five ounces and you want it to be really five ounces it's really
helpful to have a kitchen scale so that's a good one. Not very expensive and you can buy them anywhere.
The next thing I love and this is maybe not something everybody has is a food meal and what I
like is something ends up with texture so it's not just like baby food. Potatoes I actually like
finely pureed so that's different. Okay that's my food meal. I just adore it and two things for
easy cleanup. One is parchment paper and I love to line sheet pans with parchment paper so that
all you have to do is throw the paper out and you've got a nice clean pan. Well you have to put
it in the dishwasher but it's not like crusty and this is the other cleanup thing that I adore
which is my wrap and snap. Instead of fighting with that box all you do is just pull this out
really simply just cut it off and you have a really simple piece of plastic wrap. I use it all the
time. It's just great. Okay I've got one more thing to show you. Actually I've got two more things to
show you. First I'm going to show you this and it's not for ice cream. What I do is I use this
just a regular ice cream scoop for muffins, for meatballs, for anything that's round and shaped
like that and it makes perfectly proportioned meatballs and muffins and it looks very professional.
It's just an ice cream scoop you can buy in the homeware store. Okay one more thing and it's my
favorite thing in the kitchen. I'll be right back. And I'm looking for good vanilla, homemade vanilla.
This is just what I'm looking for. Might tell you about this. Okay this is it. This is my homemade
vanilla. This has been going for 35 years. What I did was I took a jar and I put vanilla beans in it.
They're expensive but you don't have to do it very often and then I poured in vodka. You use
very inexpensive vodka. It's no time for grey goose and I filled the jar with vanilla and vodka and
the liquid after about four or six months becomes vanilla extract and the smell is just amazing.
And also the vanilla beans, the seeds inside become liquid so you just snip off the top and you squeeze
the beans out. So if you're making something that like a vanilla pudding or a vanilla cake,
you can see the seeds in it and it just is so flavorful. It's like that kind of bitter thing
that's great with something sweet. So that's my vanilla and it's really easy to make. Merry Christmas
gift. Okay that's a tour of my kitchen. I know this is going to be unusual Thanksgiving but I think
it's important to find joy in the small things, the simple things and to make it a real celebration
because the holidays really kind of mark important dates and if we lose that we'll lose the whole thing
and so have a wonderful Thanksgiving. Cook a lot, share with everybody and have a very good time.
Happy Thanksgiving everybody.
Is that all right? That was so great. Okay good.