See, that's great, that's what we want.
Oops, shrimp overboard.
Who wants to catch this in their mouth?
That's good.
Hi, I'm Eric Kim.
I'm a cooking columnist for The New York Times.
Today we're gonna make a very, very simple
but effective shrimp fried rice with yum yum sauce.
This recipe is sort of inspired by
Connie House in Atlanta, Georgia.
And I sort of describe it as the Benihana of my hometown.
And every time I go back home,
I kind of crave that hibachi flavor.
The way they cook with that high heat is so special.
It's a really special way to cook vegetables, rice, shrimp.
So this recipe is inspired by that.
We're gonna make a shrimp fried rice
and then we're gonna make the yum yum sauce
and just jackson pollock it all over the rice at the end.
It's just a really over the top way to enjoy
something that is ordinarily quite simple.
I've got a large nonstick skillet.
It's the largest I've got.
If you have a cast iron skillet that works really well,
like a nice seasoned one.
And I'm actually just using frozen peeled and deveined shrimp.
With something as quick cooking as shrimp,
it kind of doesn't matter.
This is smoking, which actually is a good sign.
The goal is to imbue the oil with shrimp flavor
and that oil will flavor the rest of the dish.
Season with salt, garlic powder.
I love garlic powder.
The garlic powder is because I don't feel like
chopping garlic.
The reason I'm cooking the shrimp first
is because I wanna get it just until it's like perfectly
cooked, but if I were to add it with the rice
and frying the hot rice with everything at the end,
it would make the shrimp overcooked.
And so what you're doing is you're just folding it in
at the end.
While that's going, I'm going to chop my onion.
I love onion in my fried rice.
I don't know, I just, I like,
I like when it's barely cooked actually.
You know, just like chunks of it.
You're almost deep frying them, you know?
Okay, pretty happy with that.
Slotted spoon, I just wanna remove them.
You have all this incredible shrimp oil.
Sokidem is what my mom would call it.
Anyway, this is the shrimp oil.
We're gonna finish our fried rice in it now.
We're gonna fry the onion and stuff.
Frozen mixed vegetables.
I think a lot of people use them.
I grew up using them.
I always have these in my freezer.
I'm gonna add a cup and a half to the hot pan.
You know, these vegetables, they're all kind of sweet.
And they also cook and thaw at the same rate.
I think that's why they work really well.
I'm also gonna add the onion now.
And I like when my onion is barely cooked.
It doesn't have its raw edge anymore.
It's been slightly tempered by the heat.
And so right now, we're really just trying to thaw it.
Get it less raw.
And we're gonna add the rice pretty soon now.
One thing that is important to know
about frozen vegetables is they're already cooked.
They're blanched.
They're picked right when they're like perfect.
It's not actually that you're cooking the vegetables.
They're already cooked.
You are just thawing them basically now.
And on top of everything,
it's cooking in that glorious shrimp oil, right?
And so I'm also gonna season a little with salt.
I don't want the onion to cook too much.
So this is actually looking good to me.
As it's going, I'm gonna grab the rice.
I'm adding six cups of cooked white rice.
So that's six.
This is, I'm just gonna add it all.
So our sauce goes in.
And you know, the soy sauce is by taste,
but I have measurements in the recipe
so that you have a place to start.
This is what my mom does.
It's the mom, two spoon, two spatula, like toss.
One of the first things I ever made was fried rice.
It was home at class in fifth grade.
The teacher was teaching fried rice
and her fried rice recipe was so weird to me
because it had like uncle Ben's white rice
and like canned cheese and carrots
and then like soy sauce and that's it.
Now remember we made it and I ate it
and I was like, why does it taste so bad?
Even when I made it at home, I was like, okay,
how do I make it taste more like my mom's
or like the fried rice as I grew up loving.
And I kind of learned later
that it really does have to do with the high heat.
My mom always calls it poon mat fire taste.
What I'm actually gonna do is leave it now.
Just really let it go.
This will take about like five or so minutes.
Oh, that's a good, you see that?
That's like a good sign.
I never thought I would be showing people
how to make fried rice.
It's just like not something I've ever thought
to write a recipe for.
I don't know, it's always just,
this is just like kind of what I eat.
You know, it's what I make for myself with leftover rice
and sometimes when I'm just craving it.
We can add our eggs now.
I think a lot of people add the,
they scrambled the egg first actually
and then they add the rice and the vegetables and all that
but I scooched it all over to one side
and this is a way to just make sure you're only,
you're cooking the egg just until it's set.
You know, like I like a soft set scramble
and in this empty space,
I'm adding two tablespoons of butter.
While doing this also,
the fried rice continues to crisp, you know,
as it's like waiting for you to do this egg part
which is only gonna take a minute.
I like a lot of egg to rice personally.
So this recipe calls for four eggs.
Sort of this is my scrambled egg method in general
but just really break up the yolks
and really like scramble it
just until it's pretty set
but not hard and rubbery, you know.
It's this like vigorous stirring of the egg
that will make it really fluffy
and it will make the curds pretty like soft set
which I think is lovely.
You need to cook it enough
before you fold it back into the rice
because you don't want the rice to get all like gunky.
Okay, this is perfect.
Off the heat.
I'm gonna fold it into the egg.
Actually, this is the step
at which I would just add back the shrimp
and then now you're just mixing.
You know, I don't want the egg to cook anymore.
I don't want the shrimp to cook anymore.
I'm really just doing this now.
Ooh, that's gorgeous actually.
When I developed this recipe,
I made so many versions
and they all kind of tasted too boring for some reason.
That's where the yum yum sauce comes in.
Yum yum sauce is usually served
at Japanese American restaurants and steak houses
similar to mayo based kind of ketchup sauces.
Dehydrated garlic, AKA garlic powder and sweet paprika.
They can get a little grainy
and so I think it's a really good idea
to first mix them with a little bit of warm water.
Water from a recently boiled kettle is like good enough.
Almost like hydrating it
so that it's not so grainy in the final product.
And then we're gonna do about half a cup of mayonnaise
and a quarter cup of ketchup,
a little bit of rice vinegar.
You want a little bit of balance in the form of sourness
and I like to add a little toasted sesame oil.
It's my touch.
It's sort of this nuttiness
that really rounds out the sauce
and it kind of makes you...
Sorry.
You want a little runny.
That's another thing about the water.
It kind of thins it out.
You know, you could even thin it out further
if you would like, but I'm pretty happy with this.
That's really gonna like, I think, bring us home.
Okay, yum yum sauce is done.
It's very yummy.
The fried rice is done.
It's got a little crispiness on the bottom
because we let it sit while I finish the sauce.
This is the part where I'm just gonna go for it.
It's really over the top.
But it's something that I really love.
You don't have to do the yum yum,
but it's pretty awesome with the rice, you know?
It was a taste of the, you know, the fire
because we did high heat
and then a little piece of shrimp
with some yum yum sauce.
Oh, that's egg.
That's a nice bite.
Cooking the shrimp separately like that
is really important because it's cooked just right now.
It started the dish and ends the dish
and that's why I love this recipe.
And the fried rice tastes like
exactly how I think fried rice should taste, so.