When the blender purrs, your sauce is ready.
Smoking like a cat owner, right?
Hi, I'm Melissa Clark, and I'm here in the NIT cooking studio kitchen to make Peruvian
chicken.
In Peru, they don't call it Peruvian chicken, obviously.
Peruvian chicken is the American term for what's basically a spit roasted chicken that
you find all over Latin America.
The key to making this chicken at home in your oven is to use really high heat.
What you're trying to do is get a burnished crisp skin, which is the hallmark of a delicious
Peruvian chicken.
What makes Peruvian chicken specific is that the chilies that it's marinated in come from
Peru.
There are two distinct kinds, ahi amarillo and ahi panca.
In order to get the sort of grilled vibe of the chicken, you don't want to cook it whole.
You want to cut it in half.
I'm going to use some shears here.
You can definitely have your butcher do this if you don't want to deal with the chicken,
but it's so easy.
I thought I would just show you how to do it in case you have a whole chicken and you'd
like to dispatch it yourself.
Basically, I'm just going to cut it through the backbone or next to the backbone, and
then I'm going to cut it through the breast.
The tail is going to be your guide.
Just go to the tail and just cut along all the way in.
Crunch.
It's very satisfying that sound.
Did you get it Milton?
You could cut the backbone out entirely or you could leave it on depending on if you
like that little nubby tail, which I actually really do.
Or you could cut it off and then just use the backbone for stock.
For this one, I'm going to cut it off just because it'll be a slightly neater presentation.
I'm going to get it started with my knife and I'm going to go through the breast bone
right here.
It just makes it easier.
There we go.
I have a plastic bag in the freezer with my little chicken parts.
When it gets filled up, I make stock.
Let me wash my hands.
Okay.
It's a really straightforward marinade.
This is the ahi amariyo yellow and this is the ahi panca.
If you can't find it and you want to make this dish, you can substitute other chili
pastes.
You need a lot of garlic for this.
This is six cloves of garlic.
You can mince them or just grate them on a little microplane, lime juice for acidity,
soy sauce, mustard, ground cumin, salt and pepper.
Just give it a whisk.
Then I'm just going to coat it really nicely.
Get under the wings, but you don't have to worry about going under the skin.
It's going to get there.
Thank you.
Put it in the fridge between two and 12 hours.
You don't want to leave this for more than 12 hours because at that point the chicken
is going to start to, the texture is going to be affected.
It's going to start to get a little bit soft because of the acidity.
So 12 hours is your max.
What I want to do now is I want to pat it dry because the moisture is going to inhibit
browning.
Since this is really all about the burnished, gorgeous, crisp skin, if you don't pat it
down, you're not going to get there.
The chicken at this point has really absorbed all the good flavors of the marinade.
Don't feel bad about patting it off.
It has done its work.
I'm just going to go wash my hands.
This is just a little bit of olive oil.
The olive oil is going to help crisp the skin.
Just drizzle it on just a little.
Now we're going to put it straight away in the oven.
This is the thing.
If you don't usually put your oven at 450 and your oven isn't pretty clean, you might
notice some smoke.
I'm just warning you.
It's normal.
So don't be alarmed if your oven gets a little smoky.
That is the temperature you need.
It's going to take about 35-45 minutes.
If your oven is at all uneven, and actually most ovens are pretty uneven, halfway through
cooking, just turn the tray around.
That way it will brown evenly.
So while the chicken is roasting, we can make the sauce.
The sauce for this kind of chicken varies with the cook.
There is no one kind of green sauce that goes with it.
When I developed the recipe, I tried many different combinations and this was the one.
I was like, yes, this is the sauce.
So for all you cilantro haters out there, if you don't want to use cilantro, you can
substitute another green.
You just want to make sure it has a really fresh flavor.
My new favorite cilantro substitute is arugula.
Actually, baby arugula, because it has a peppery brightness.
It's a different flavor, but I like it.
There are so many things in the sauce, but they work together and they really harmonize
well.
So I'm going to get this going and then I'm going to slowly drizzle in the olive oil.
How do you know when the sauce is blended enough?
Well, one way is you look at it and you see that there are no big chunks.
But another way to tell is you listen.
You're going to hear the change from everything being solid, ingredients kind of bumping around
until it gets quiet and like a little, like a purrs.
When the blender purrs, your sauce is ready.
It's bright green.
It's very smooth and silky looking.
So I'm going to try it.
Oh, it's so good.
You're tasting for salt and acidity.
You add a little more salt, a little more pepper.
I actually think this is perfect the way it is, so I'm not going to add any of it, but
you need to taste it because you never know.
And the chicken is ready.
I'm going to get it and we're going to feast.
Oh, it's gorgeous.
You can see the color.
Look at that, the crisp skin, the beautiful, really dark golden brown.
Now you want to let it rest for a couple of minutes, just like five, 10 minutes tops while
you set the table, pour the sauce into a bowl, get everything all ready.
It doesn't need a long rest.
It doesn't need like a 20 minute turkey rest.
It's so good.
It's so flavorful.
The meat is juicy.
The skin is crisp.
That sauce is amazing.
I want it on everything.
Bright, vibrant, pungent, salty, umami, all of the things.
For the recipe, we have a free link below.
So click on it, make it, leave us a comment.
We want to hear from you.
And enjoy.
It's such a good recipe.
Wow.
If I do say so myself.
You don't mind if I sit underneath this, do you?